Graph on me Good afternoon I am Ashish Sher,
interview on
your topic, tell me I have
just completed my B.Com from Charan Singh University
and I am very interested in doing business
in the banking sector
because the subject I have studied in my B.Com is
Financial Analysis,
how does the banking sector work
and I have a lot of good internship
experience, I have previously done an
internship in Mutual Finance where I studied
in the field of Loan and Financing
and I have a lot of expectations
that I will like the banking sector
and if I
talk a little about my family then there are five of us in my family,
my father is a farmer and
I studied very hard and I
want to work in the banking sector
and advance my career,
why do you want to join the banking industry, the
banking sector is a very fast growing
sector, there are a
lot of growth opportunities in the banking sector
because just like the banking sector is growing, similarly the
employees in the banking sector also have a
lot of growth opportunities, I have been working in
banks since childhood  I used to go into
banking with my father when I was young, so the
bank employees are
respected a lot, they
get a lot of respect within the bank as well as the
society respects them and I
want to do something that will
create importance for me,
banking gives opportunity,
first of all banking
plays a big role in developing the economy of the country
and in this way I can also serve the country
and at the same time through banking
we can go up to graduate, those who have the
mission of financial inclusion can
help people at the grass root level, we
can empower them, so this is
my motive and my skill set,
my education aligns with it, so
my motive is to work in the
banking sector, not only to
start my career but also to reach
very good positions in the banking sector in the long term, so this is my motivation, I
want to work in the banking sector, so
why do you want to work in our bank, when
you have a lot of experience  You have asked an interesting question.
Look, there are many banks. There are
22 very big banks among the private banks.
When someone wants to join
ICC, it is because of the professionalism that I have seen
in many banks. I have worked in many banks and some of my
friends are already working in the banking sector. So, from what
I have seen so far, the
welfare schemes for the staff in ICC Bank are good. The remuneration is also
good and there are opportunities for growth.
Definitely, there is
growth and possibilities in all the other banks as well. But I got very good
feedback about ICC Bank from my friend that
if you work in the bank and
perform, then your efforts are
also recognized. You
also get good sentences and on the
basis of your performance, you
get good opportunities for growth. And here I will get to
learn a lot because the training that the
bank provides to ICC Bank is
very comprehensive
and I will get to learn a lot from it.
I will have scale development and at the same time, as
I said earlier, growth.  There are
many opportunities and it is a very
respected bank. Customers trust Peace Bank a lot, so that is why
I am
more interested in working with this bank.
Compared to other banks, I have a
lot of knowledge about banking, so tell me
what are the banking products. It is a
very interesting question. Banks have many
products like
different kinds of accounts like savings,
different kinds of insurance which banks
provide like
health insurance,
wealth insurance and many of the
products of banks are
in the loan category. Loan is a very
important product through which we can empower
those people to fulfill their dreams
like home loan, vehicle
loan, education loan, there are different kinds of loans for
agriculture
like Kisan Credit Card schemes
and banks also offer many different types of loans to
cooperatives and companies, so
cards play a very big role like credit card or debit
card.  There are products in this bank
and they provide a lot of financial services,
wealth management services,
equity products, mutual
funds, and wealth creation
products. So, there can be
many different
product lines within the bank, and
that's why I believe there are a lot of growth opportunities within the bank
because we can support the general public and
businesses equally.
We can support both of them in
wealth creation and
in fulfilling their aspirations. Like you said, you did an
internship in the finance department. So,
Shikha, I had a
very good experience there. Like
I said, I did a job in the gold loan department. I had an
internship of 3 months there. I learned a lot within those three months. So,
I would
like to highlight three of my learnings.
First of all, I gained a lot of knowledge about the finance sector
when we
read something in books and when we do practicals.
Definitely, the knowledge we have gained from studying books is
less, but when
we implement it practically, we face a lot of
challenges. So, I learned
how the financing sector works in the real world.
Second, my biggest learning
was lead generation. Whenever we have to do
business for any bank or finance company,
lead generation
plays a huge role. How do we understand to
whom we can sell
or cross-sell? So, what
is the process of lead generation?
How can we generate leads through online and offline campaign marketing in different ways? I learned that. And
my biggest learning was
how to pitch our product
because if we are able to explain the
benefits and features of our product well, only then will
someone
buy our product and only then will he have
confidence in us because there are a
lot of people in the market who provide services. So,
if we do
not pitch our product well, then we will
not be able to convert, we will not be able to bring business.
So how can we do our business?  How to give a presentation and how to
focus on the benefits, so this
was a big learning for me and I really believe that
my learning will
come less in this time, it was my introduction of only three
months, I learned so much there,
but I
want to practice it more practically so that I
expect that in this time I will get a lot of
opportunities, there is a lot of
learning in the sector and there are challenges in every
time, so I faced challenges in this sector
too, there are a
lot of challenges in these townships too, the biggest
challenge I faced was to learn those things
because as I said earlier,
in education we have to learn a lot of things, we have
a set parameter in our mind, but the
word practical means something a little differently,
we have to be smart, we have to
handle things smartly,
so I had to unlock that a little, I had to
leave old things and accept new things, so first of all, there was a mental
roadblock, I
cleared that,
secondly, I got to learn the team,
although it was very challenging for me in the beginning.
Because till now we do
studies, so we have independence,
but when we
came to practical in internship, then how to
communicate properly, how to work properly with everyone, that was a bit
challenging for me in the beginning and I am
very happy to say that when I
completed my internship, I was highly
appreciated that I
am a good team player and my communication
skills are very good, so I
admit in myself that it was a challenge which I
overcame a lot of confidence and the
third thing I feel is about confidence,
when I used to talk to someone in the beginning,
initially
I used to feel a lot of hesitation in pitching my product,
my confidence level was a little low,
so I practiced that again and again, so
I have overcome that challenge as well,
no I am more confident when ever I am talking, so okay very good,
what is your biggest strength and what is your weakness,
yes I very much like a different type of
question, this is  My strength
is the strength of BJP, first I
would like to tell you about that, my strength is learning
ability, I can learn things very quickly, I
observe and I believe in
learning by doing, I
like to learn things by doing and I believe it helps me a lot
in being practical, I can learn things quickly
and get results quickly, this is my
biggest strength and if I talk about my weakness in business, then my weakness is
communication skills, my
communication skills are not that strong yet in English,
I can put my buttons well in Hindi,
but if we
look at the long term prospective, then
I will have to learn good communication skills
in English and I am working on it, I have
joined online courses,
I am practicing them,
preparing and I am very
confident that very soon I will
convert my weakness into strength, if he is
shouting at you and getting angry then
you should handle the situation  How will you handle it?
Yes, it is a very important question
because the banking sector is a service sector
and it is
our responsibility to keep everyone happy and satisfied here,
but many times it can happen that sometimes the
customer's expectations are very high
and
they can expect something from us even if it goes against the bank policy. And
here sometimes it can also happen that
because of me or other staff, if
I do not meet the customer's expectations, then it is
red land, they can get angry,
but one should know how to handle this situation very well
and I believe that during my
internship, I got to learn a lot about
how to satisfy an angry person.
So now I would like to share with you the
steps that I will take. First of all, to
calm down an angry customer, I will
first listen to him and find out why he
is angry. Many times, customers get angry
because they are not being heard
and they keep getting hyper. So, first of all,
I will lovingly ask him to sit,
offer him water and
ask him,  Sir, please tell me your problem
in detail. When the customer
tells you in detail, he may get very angry,
but I will
listen to him. As I
listen to him, my personal experience says
that the customer slowly starts calming down,
he feels that yes, his point is being heard.
When I am listening to him, I will also
ensure him that he tells me the
whole story in full detail
so that I can give him the best solution.
When the customer tells me the whole story,
I will analyze whether it is the customer's
fault or there has been some mistake from our side. Then
I will give the customer a
primary level solution. Today, on the basis of
bank policy, how can this situation be handled?
Many times it can be said that there is
some miscommunication and if we make
some promise about it within the bank policy, then the
customer will definitely calm down.
But if the customer's
expectation is such that we
cannot follow it according to the policy, then  We will
tell you to what extent we can support the customer politely. They will request the customer to cooperate. If the situation
calms down then it is well and good, otherwise we
can ask him to calm down for some time.
We will escalate this complaint to our frontline department
and discuss
what possible solution we
can find for this. For some time
I will try to calm the customer down and send him back. On the
back end I will decide
how we can solve his problem. I will
keep the communication open with the customer during this time so that the customer gets the update
and the customer remains in control. The customer remains
calm and does not talk negativity about our matter after any other customer.
I will keep the customer in confidence.
As soon as the final solution is found, we will
communicate with the customer and
make sure that he either gets a solution to his
complaint or his
demand is reasonable. He should have clarity on
why his demand is reasonable and I will
try my best.  The customer
satisfaction level is very high.
As I asked you a lot of questions,
through that I
tried to give you confidence that I have
knowledge of this banking sector, I have
skills. You must have seen in the interview
that I also have experience in this
sector and I have a lot of
interest in this sector. I want to work in this
industry for a long term
and I want to assure you
that along with these skills and
abilities, I had said that I will work hard
and bring results. I am always a
result oriented candidate. I
believe in results and I believe in hard work.
So I will leave my hard work
and my hard work and you will get results for the bank.
My skills will help in that and the
bank will give me a good platform so that I can
give results. Therefore, I would
request you to please consider me
for this position. Let's
start with the
dedicated one year structure of banks,
which is the standard norm for this position.
I am ready because I know the salary.
Along with this, there are good in-sentences in the banking sector as
well, so I believe in me
hard work and I hope that as I work hard, I will get
promotions as well and
with promotions there will be increments as well, so for now I am
happy with the standard structure, right now
I am going out to spend
some time with my family,
so if possible I would
like to join from next Monday, so is it ok but
you can do that,
thank you